In a skills résumé, you present the skills section at the start. This organization lets you emphasize your professional attributes. Notice that the writer uses specific details—names of software, number of credits, types of documents, kinds of activities—to make her case.

The employment section contains a list of positions rather than descriptions of what the writer did in each position.

The volunteer position says something about the writer's character.

The writer believes that the skills required in raising children are relevant in the workplace. Other applicants might think that because a résumé describes job credentials, this information should be omitted.

```
Alice P. Linder
1781 Weber Road
Rawlings, MT 59211
(406) 555-3999
linderap423@gmail.com
SUMMARY
Biotechnology major with broad laboratory experience at Glaxo-
SmithKline, analyzing molecular data and writing C# programs.
Working toward Certification in laboratory specialty through
ASCP. Strong written and oral communication skills. Extensive
volunteer experience in physical therapy for children. Experi-
ence managing business office.
SKILLS AND ABILITIES
Laboratory Skills
-Analyzed molecular data on E&S PS300, Macintosh, and IBM PCs.
Wrote programs in C#.
-Have taken 12 credits in biology and chemistry labs.
Communication Skills
-Wrote a user's guide for an instructional computing package.
-Trained and consulted with scientists and delivered in-house
briefings.
Management Skills
-Managed 12-person office in $1.2 million company.
EDUCATION
Central Montana State University, Rawlings, MT
BS in Bioscience and Biotechnology
Expected Graduation Date: 6/2015
Related Course Work
General Chemistry I, II, III
Biology I, II, III
Organic Chemistry I, II
Calculus I, II
Statistical Methods for Research
Physics I, II
Technical Communication
EMPLOYMENT EXPERIENCE
6/2012-present (20 hours per week): Laboratory Assistant Grade 3
GlaxoSmithKline, Rawlings, MT
8/2009-present: Volunteer, Physical Therapy Unit
Rawlings Regional Medical Center, Rawlings, MT
6/2001-1/2004: Office Manager
Anchor Products, Inc., Rawlings, MT
HONORS
Awarded three $5,000 tuition scholarships (2011-2013) from the
Gould Foundation.
ADDITIONAL INFORMATION
Member, CMSU Biology Club, Yearbook Staff
Raising three school-age children
Tuition 100% self-financed
```

FIGURE 15.5 Skills Résumé of a Nontraditional Student